Khodor Ammar

Hi. I'm a developer with a decade of digital experience. I'm attentive to details, I support open-source, I'm excited about javascript, and currently in love with Node.js. I lead teams to go the extra mile and strive to generate the best outcome. In my free time I read fantasy books.

Technical skills

I'm fluent in Javascript, HTML, CSS, and everything React. I'm confident in .NET and SQL. I know my way around PHP. I'm comfortable working with AWS, and I work daily on improving my skill set and on learning new tricks.

Experience

2017 - Present

Technical Lead at Hogarth World Wide (https://www.hogarthww.com/) in Dubai, UAE

In 2017 I've joined HogarthWW as a Technical lead for one of the company's biggest clients, I'm leading a dedicated team and working closely with multiple teams both on Hogarth and client side.

2014 - 2017

Technical Lead at Prototype Interactive (https://prototype.net) in Dubai, UAE

In 2014 I've moved to Dubai to join a lead role in Prototype, I lead the development and helped establishing the company's technical vision. Ensured code quality and best practices. Recruited and grew the team.

2009 - 2014

Lead Web Developer at STeP (http://www.step-stp.com) in Beirut, Lebanon

Education

2009

MS In Web Development from the Lebanese University, Faculty of Sciences II

2008

BS in Computer Science from the Lebanese University, Faculty of Sciences I

Hackathons

2017

Winner, Battle of the bots.

With the Help of IBM Watson, we've built a witty chatbot that competed and won againt other chatbots.

2015

Winner, Hackamena.

With a team of three, I've built a life-saving app to allow cardiac arrest witnesses to signal for help from nearby CPR-trained people, who would rush to start CPR before the Emergency services arrive.

Languages

My native language is Arabic, but I'm fluent in English. I know enough French to not get lost in Paris.

Others

Since 2007, I'm a certified Emergency Medical Technician at the Lebanese Red Cross. In addition, I'm a trainer in leadership, teamwork, and conflict resolution.

Contact (khodor.ammar@gmail.com)
Github (https://github.com/KhodorAmmar)
Linkedin (https://www.linkedin.com/in/khodorammar)